const text = {
    title: "Interview with Joshua Singh",
    start: "We have been wanting to do this interview for quite some time but now we finally managed to do it." +
     "There probably has not been that much to talk about with 1423 and S.B.S in quite some time, but read for yourself",
    content: [
      {question: "Would you like to introduce yourself, 1423 and S.B.S?",
      answer:"I am Joshua Singh, Founder and export manager for 1423, we are a Danish based importer, distributor and brand owner founded in " +
      "2008 when we released our first bottle 1423 1st edition which was essentially also the predecessor to S.B.S."},
     
      {question: "How did you decide to become part of the industry and what would you do today if it weren’t for that?",
      answer: "Me and the partners in 1423 all started out as whisky drinkers and back around the beginning we used to attend various "+
      "whisky festivals around Denmark to learn and taste more about the spirit. It was at one of these festivals we were introduced to " +
      "rum for the first time and we were easily convinced that rum was a lot more interesting than whisky. Shortly after that introduction" + 
      "we started the work that eventually ended up being 1423 1st edition. If I had not been in the rum industry, I would most likely have" + 
      "been a business owner of some other venture along with my brother. We tried a number of other enterprises before I ended in rum and it " + 
      "has always been in our blood to be our own boss."},
      
      {question: "Now the audience of this blog is probably mostly interested in the S.B.S releases. " +
      "How important are they for you financially, relative to 1423s other products?",
      answer: "S.B.S is financially not a big business, however it has its merits from both being a complimentary products to our" + 
      "other brands being able to offer a full rum portfolio to our clients and also act as a fun place where we can play around," + 
      "experiment and enjoy our geeky sides of rum."},
     
      {question: "After the announced name change by Maison Ferrand’s brand Plantation, there has been a lot of criticism for your" + 
      "product “Ron Esclavo” as well. Can you tell us more about that?",
      answer: "Ron Esclavo has received a heighten attention and criticism on various social media platforms this past month." + 
      "Esclavo being the Spanish word for Slave has stirred up feelings in people around the world that was never the intention." + 
      "When we created the name almost 10 years ago, we were 4 people of Indian descent who whenever we did your tastings spend a lot" + 
      "of time talking about the triangular trade and the darker history of rum. Africans were taken away from their homes and brought to" + 
      "the plantations to work the sugar cane fields and later after they received their freedom the English started bringing over Indians" + 
      "to work as Indentured workers under terms that were close to the same. The name Esclavo was created because of that, to help tell the story and start the discussion.",},
     
      {question: "In hindsight, do you still think the name “Ron Esclavo” was a good idea?",
      answer: "Looking back today we would have chosen a different name, it was never our intention to hurt anyone and I am sorry for the" + 
      "people whom we have hurt. Today we would have gone in another direction. The next step now for us will be to change the name while" + 
      "still being able to tell the story we intended."},
     
      {question: "You have also bottled a rum for the band Rammstein. How did that come about?" + 
      "Did their management approach you? Do you also like their music?",
      answer: "Some years ago we did a bottling for the Danish rock band Volbeat, it was an idea we created after we got booked to do a" + 
      "tasting with the band members and we prepared a bottle with special label to give to the band as a fun gimmick. They liked it and" +
      "we helped them produce the first edition of their own rum. That experience we had a lot of fun with and together with my partners " + 
      "we sat down and thought about how we could do more. One name immediately sprung to mind: RAMMSTEIN! We contacted their management " + 
      "and presented them with our idea, and they loved it. Rammstein was the obvious choice as several of us like their music and if you " + 
      "ever see me in the office you will be seeing me wearing a Rammstein t-shirt 9 out of 10 days."},
     
      {question:"Something that I have been quite fond of as well are the products of the Ghanaian distillery MIM. Both, the cashew apple brandies as well as" + 
      "the rum samples I have tasted. Can you tell us more about them and your collaboration?",
      answer: "The Collaboration with MIM actually started as quite a coincidence, they approached us to help them do their first " + 
      "bottling of their cashew brandy and once we had started they came back and said “by the way, we made a rum”. It did not take many " 
      + "seconds for the first one to shout out “Why didn’t you tell us and bring us samples”. The samples we received were unique, a " + 
      "totally different profile from anything else we had tried, cane juice fermented for 5-6 days and then distilled in a pot still " 
      + "we have never seen similar in any other place. What the future will bring you will have to wait and see, we have filled some " + 
      "casks here at our warehouse that will be released under S.B.S in time, but for MIM as a brand I don’t know what their plans are " +
      "for the future.",},
     
      {question: "Which of your releases are you especially proud of and why?",
      answer:"That is a difficult one, there are too many to choose from. If I had to point out a few I would say our advent " +
      "calendar “24 Days of Rum” where we work closely with producers around the world to present 24 different rums from 24 different " 
      + "countries. The opportunity to show people the many facets of rum while giving them an opportunity to learn in the process. " + 
      "And of course, the releases we have done in collaboration with Worthy Park.",},
     
      {question: "How did the partnership with Worthy Park come about?",
      answer: "I travelled to Jamaica for summer holidays 6 years ago and spend 4 weeks on the island visiting different cities and " +
      "the 3 distilleries that I managed to get a tour at, Appleton, Hampden and Worthy Park. When I came to Worthy Park which was my " +
      "last to visit, Zan Kong had just taken over as their export manager a few months prior and I believe I was his first tour he ever " +
      "did. That tour made me fall in love with the place, the beautiful scenery, the people and of course the rum. When I came back home, " +
      "I brought samples for my team and not long after we placed the first order to get started.",},
      
      {question: "If you ask me, there are few players in the rum scene who do finishes better than you. " +
      "What separates a good finish from a bad finish?",
      answer: "A good finish or secondary ageing had to add something extra to the flavor of the original product while keeping the " +
      "rum and the base as the primary. For instance, when we do a finish on an older rum it is out of wish or idea that we can add " +
      "something extra to make it a little better. The finish however should never be overpowering the original. A good example could " 
      +"be the S.B.S Cuba 2012 double maturation we released last year, the Cuban rum in itself is rather light in both aroma and taste " +
      "but after a secondary ageing in Virgin Oak it really steps out and you get a more full bodied heavier profile that really turned " +
      "out very well.",},

      {question:"Since we have already talked about Worthy Park and finishes, you have also done finishes for them. That sort of relationship is " +
      "rather unusual, isn’t it? What was the process behind that?",
      answer: "This actually started after the German Rumfest a few years ago, me and my colleague Thomas had brought a sample from " +
      "a PX sherry cask we had filled with Worthy Park, the reception was very good and Zan who had joined us for the festival loved it " +
      "as well. At that time, it was not easy for Worthy Park themselves to start a project like this so we agreed that we would start " +
      "it up together and in time move everything to Jamaica. The release we made earlier this year will therefore also be the last and " +
      "the next release will be 100% Jamaica.",},

      {question: "Can you tell us about finishes that have gone bad? What did you do with these rums?",
      answer: "We have seen a few barrels where the wine or spirit that was left in the wood from previously had turned bad. Normally " +
       "when we receive these barrels, they are emptied for what is left and then rinsed, but in a few cases we have been unlucky. It has " +
       "happened in the past to 1 cask with Worthy Park and 1 with Foursquare. The Worthy Park we redistilled at the Danish distillery " +
       "Enghaven and the Foursquare we have left in the cask to watch what happens in time.",},
      
      {question: "You’ve recently invested heavily into a new warehouse. What can we expect from 1423 and S.B.S in the future?",
      answer: "More rum! We are always working on new projects, some will come to life while others will be forgotten. At the " +
      "moment we are planning the next release of S.B.S that will come on the market around September and will include some " +
      "experiments we have made and where we try to invite the people in to the process by bottling the same rum from different " +
      "casks so they can feel the influence.",},
     
      {question: "Which product that is completely unrelated to 1423 have you been enjoying recently?",
      answer: "The best experience I have had this year would have to be from our German friends at Rum Artesanal and the " +
      "1994 Enmore / Versailles release they did in the beginning of the year. That bottling is truly outstanding. Cheers to " +
      "Dominik and his team for choosing some really extraordinary casks.",},
      {question: "Any last words?",
      answer: "It has been a crazy year 2020 with Covid-19 raging the world, let us all hope for better days to come. " +
      "I for one look very much forward to getting back on the road, visiting rum festivals, rum people, and rum distilleries. " +
      "Travelling is a big part of my job and my life so I hope to see you and all your readers back out there again soon.",}  
    ],   
    end:"Thanks a lot, Joshua!"
}

export default text;